Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
I can cut a thousand strands of hair
but I cannot sever the tangled threads of my mind.
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Now the Household Department
only sends us the best of everything.
Everyone knows how much
His Majesty cherishes you, My Lady.
He's also instructed Dr. Wen
to bring tonics here every day.
You think of that as a treat?
The medicine's so bitter.
Speaking of bitterness, Escort Yu
has been behaving outrageously.
I heard she's been cursing you every day
since leaving the Palace of Accumulated Purity.
Let her be.
I've always acted with a clear conscience.
Her curses will be fruitless.
But her words... are too unpleasant to hear.
How about I report it to the Empress?
Her Majesty will decide for you.
That's more trouble than Yu's worth.
"Show mercy where there are grounds for forgiveness."
It's only natural that she feels resentful for losing favor.
She'll be fine after a while.
You have such a kind heart, My Lady.
My Lady, the tonic is ready.
The tonic has tasted very sour recently.
Perhaps Dr. Wen added new ingredients to it.
It hasn't been long since I got up,
but I feel sleepy again.
You've been sleeping a lot lately.
You just had a nap earlier.
Help me get ready for a nap.
Jade,
when did I begin to sleep so much?
About five days ago. You've been sleeping
for almost half the day lately.
The sun was already three poles high
when His Majesty came here last time,
but you were still asleep...
You've also sensed that is something is wrong, haven't you?
My Lady, let me bring Dr. Wen here before you nap.
Go discreetly. Say it's just for a routine pulse check.
Please pardon me, My Lady.
This will sting slightly.
This is the Hegu acupuncture point.
The needle will indicate whether your sleepiness is normal.
It changes color under the effect of certain drugs.
As expected, my herbs were tampered with.
My Lady, the tip of the needle turned light green.
What is that? Poison?
No, it's not that.
Someone increased the dosage of one ingredient,
which I prescribed to be low in weight.
They have been very discreet about the change in dosage.
It was too subtle to come to my attention in daily pulse-takings.
But if you had taken this dosage
for a prolonged period of time,
you would have experienced somnolence at first
and in under six months,
you would have become delirious and demented.
They must think highly of me,
to use such a clever method to deal with me.
It's fortunate that we caught it early.
I will prescribe counter-treatments for you, My Lady.
It is an insidious trick.
This person is clearly attempting to kill you, My Lady.
Rivalries in the harem manifest in extreme ways.
We can never be too thorough in our defense.
Dr. Wen, without your help,
I would have died in an ignorant dream.
It was my negligence that caused your suffering, My Lady.
I will be particularly careful in the future.
I will personally prepare and serve the herbs
to prevent any form of meddling.
It's important to take precautions,
but the priority should be identifying the poisoner.
The tonics were prepared in my palace according to your prescriptions.
If someone could interfere in my palace,
they must be someone serving by my side.
Several new servants were sent to your
palace last month.
And the tonics tasted different after that.
In that case, we have to pay attention to the
new maids and eunuchs.
What is your plan, My Lady?
I hope Dr. Wen can put on a performance with me.
We will act as if nothing happened,
so as not to "beat the grass and alert the snakes."
I'm at your disposal, My Lady.
Thank you, Dr. Wen.
I'm relieved to hear that I'm all right.
It's normal to feel fatigued in the spring.
You might as well take this opportunity to get more rest.
Thank you, Dr. Wen.
My Lady, I found a movable brick on the courtyard wall.
It wasn't there until recently.
"Trouble resides within one's own screen walls."
Pretend that you don't know.
Watch the courtyard with Xiao-Yunzi
when they brew the herbs tomorrow.
They'll be caught surprised and red-handed.
Yes, My Lady. Xiao-Yunzi knows kungfu.
He won't let the turncoats get away.
I bow in respect before Your Majesty.
I bow in respect before Your Highnesses.
Rise. Have a seat.
I thank Your Majesty.
Seeing Lady Shen in good health,
I can finally put my mind at ease.
Lady Shen's accidental fall
turned out to be a blessing in disguise.
It gained her care and visits from His Majesty,
a blessing some of us can only wish for.
Indeed.
These days, I've been wondering why people are
swarming to the Thousand Carp Pond.
But I've got my head around it now.
They must be waiting to plop down into the water
and then fall into His Majesty's favor.
You are funny, Concubine Beauté.
Why would anyone imperil their own life?
Of course not.
Lady Shen has been in high favor.
Only aged and infirm women would turn over every stone
to attract His Majesty.
Your Highness's words truly scare me.
We will all live to a day of old age.
I must pray to Buddha in the Baohua Hall
to bless me with eternal youthfulness
like Your Highness.
The Buddha has too many prayers to answer.
Our actions matter more than our prayers.
Lady Shen, I heard that Lady Sourire was always
by your side when you were unwell.
I wonder where she is today.
The bond of sisterhood cannot withstand His Majesty's favor.
I heard that His Majesty invited Lady Sourire to his study.
That's why she's absent today.
No wonder.
Such is sisterhood in the palace.
We were on guard the whole time.
Violet was looking over the stove and no one approached.
It's still contaminated.
We were negligent. Please forgive us, My Lady.
It's not entirely your fault.
The tonic was tampered with right under your noses
without anyone else near the brewing pot.
There must be something amiss.
Jade, discard the tonic later, secretly.
Yes.
What are you looking at?
My Lady, I was thinking if no one laid a finger on the herbs,
there must be something wrong with the utensils.
Let me have a look.
I don't see anything wrong with it.
Are we thinking of this the wrong way?
Look,
the color of the lid seems to be darker than the pot.
Aiyo!
It is.
You can only spot the difference when you look closely.
Why is that?
Is it because the lid was simmered in poison for a long time
and absorbed the color of the poisonous herbs?
My Lady, your tonic comes into contact with the lid when it boils.
That's how the poison made its way into the tonic.
What a sophisticated technique!
No wonder our efforts were to no avail.
They were "keeping a lid" on it all along.
Who is taking care of the utensils?
It used to be me, but I gave them to Spica, the new maid.
- Xiao-Yunzi.
- Yes.
Discard the tonic and put the pot back.
Do it discreetly.
And inquire about Spica's background for me.
Mr. Yun.
Spica, why did you sneak behind my back?
Mr. Yun, what brings you to the kitchen?
I hope you can pardon the sootiness.
I am the head eunuch of the palace.
I go anywhere I want.
If I didn't come, how would I know you're still using
that shabby old pot to brew tonics for My Lady?
It looks as if My Lady has fallen from grace.
Get a new one immediately.
Sir, you might not know this.
But an older pot brews better medicine.
A new pot can change the potency of the herbs.
You always know better, don't you?
We'll keep the pot for now.
Keep up your good work. It'll not go unnoticed.
By the way, My Lady is napping after taking the tonic.
You should have the evening tonic ready on time.
My Lady, I've found out that Spica used to serve Escort Yu.
She was one of the maids
who were sent away upon Yu's demotion.
She was later assigned here.
Looks like she's using her hooves to avenge Yu.
What a maid - still loyal to her old mistress.
Bring her here to see me.
Yes.
Oh, get some burning charcoal from the kitchen -
the red-hot pieces.
They'll come in handy.
Good to see you here, Jade.
My Lady's tonic is almost ready.
No rush, I will stay here for a bit.
Dr. Wen said these herbs are the most nourishing for My Lady.
I've been carefully watching the stove the whole time.
Spica, although you are a newcomer,
you are very loyal to My Lady.
It is an honor to serve in the Palace of Pearl Jade.
I must devote myself.
My Lady appreciates your devotion.
She wishes to reward you.
You should go quickly.
My Lady wishes to reward me?
Go quickly. My Lady is waiting.
Bring the brazier with you to keep the tonic warm.
Raise your head. We won't eat you.
Don't be scared.
I simply want to ask a few questions.
Jinxi told me that you have been a competent maid,
keeping things in order.
I appreciate that.
I'm wondering what I should reward you
so that the other servants will follow your example.
Thank you, My Lady. It's my duty.
You stand out from the new servants in my palace.
I wonder which palace you used to work for.
Why would your mistress send you away?
I was too humble to work for any notable concubine.
I am honored to be in your service, My Lady.
It must be the good karma from my past lives.
Escort Yu is not a notable concubine
due to her demotion.
But what did she offer you
to make you commit such a heinous capital offense?
My Lady, I did serve Escort Yu,
but I have no idea what you're talking about.
You really don't know what I'm talking about?
What happened to the lid of my brewing pot?
I have no idea!
I am loyal to you, My Lady!
I trust you are clear-sighted.
If you say you're loyal, we will give you
a chance to show your loyalty.
My Lady has to be cautious
because you have worked for Escort Yu.
If you can hold a piece of this charcoal in your hand,
you can prove your innocence and loyalty.
And we all will treat you kindly.
Do it!
You're scared, aren't you?
How false your loyalty is!
Please spare me, My Lady.
Please spare me!
Tell me the truth.
A single word of falsehood will get you flogged to death.
One day, after I was sent to the Palace of Pearl Jade,
Escort Yu asked me to see her.
She gave me a lot of gold and silver,
and forced me to do this for her.
I'm such a fool, My Lady!
I beg your forgiveness, My Lady!
Go on, this is your chance to atone for your crime.
But I won't tolerate any dishonesty.
Escort Yu said all I needed to do
was to put poison in your food and tonics.
I pried off a brick on the wall at Yu's command.
She had messages passed to me through the hole
so I knew her orders and what to do with the items.
Is that how the poison was passed in?
And she taught you the sly trick of
simmering the lid in poison?
Yes.
Do you have any accomplices?
No, there's no one else!
When does Yu send in messages and poison?
She...
Xiao-Yunzi, put the charcoal in her mouth!
I'll tell! I'll tell!
Yu sends in the poison every other day
for me to pick it up.
Every other day? So tonight?
What time is the pick-up?
Is there a secret code word?
When the first night watch sounds [7 PM],
someone makes a cuckoo sound on the other side of the wall.
I make a cuckoo sound in response.
Did you see who it was?
No, I couldn't see through the wall.
But I know it's a man from his hand.
There's a scar in the palm of his right hand.
Xiao-Yunzi, tie her up in the storeroom.
Keep her alive.
If anyone asks, say she's been sent to Lady Shen.
Go!
Jinxi, you will pick up the poison in place of Spica.
Select a few eunuchs to wait around with Xiao-Yunzi.
Yes, I'll do that right away.
I need to tell Meizhuang about this.
Yes, it's a good idea to inform Lady Shen and make a plan with her.
What about Companion An?
Let's not give trouble to Lingrong.
She has a faint heart.
Just as well.
My Lady, you must make up your mind now.
You can't be so forgiving this time.
My Lady, Xiao-Yunzi is up on the roof.
He'll jump down and catch the culprit alive.
I'll be standing by the wall.
It's good that Xiao-Yunzi knows kungfu.
He's well disguised by the darkness.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Got him!
Xiao-Yunzi, we got him!
Go, go quickly!
Go get him!
Go!
- Let me go! I'm begging you!
- Behave yourself!
- Let me go!
- Behave!
- Please let me go!
- On your knees!
My Lady, please let me go!
Hold up his head.
I'm afraid it's an old acquaintance.
Xiao-Yinzi?
Mr. Yin, I trust you've been well.
Peace to Lady Sourire.
Although it's been a while since we last met,
we were once mistress and servant.
Answer whatever questions I ask.
Are the rods in place?
Yes, My Lady.
Who do you work for currently?
For Escort Yu.
That must be a waste of your talent.
I'm just a servant.
A servant doesn't get to pick his mistress.
It's good that you think like that.
Didn't you follow your shifu to work for Concubine Beauté?
Why were you sent to Escort Yu?
Shifu offended Concubine Beauté
for his intention to come back to you, My Lady.
Concubine Beauté began to disdain me as well.
Her Highness sent me to serve Escort Yu
as a chance to redeem myself.
Concubine Beauté plans far ahead
for you, doesn't she?
Now tell me, what were you doing
outside my palace this time at night?
I...
- Xiao-Yunzi.
- Yes.
Slap this treacherous ingrate
until he speaks the truth.
Please spare me, My Lady!
My Lady...
please spare me... My Lady!
I am telling the truth!
Please spare me!
My Lady, that weasel couldn't stand the torture
and confessed everything.
He said that Escort Yu ordered him to do this.
Tie him up and send him to the storeroom.
Keep watch on him and Spica.
I feel bitterly, bitterly disappointed.
I treated him so nicely.
Don't feel disappointed by that muck.
Now it is clear that Yu is harbouring a grudge and wants to take revenge.
I have been amply tolerant towards Yu.
But when I give her an inch, she takes an ell.
Meizhuang, why is it so difficult
to have some peace in the palace?
"While you have no intention to hurt the tiger,
the tiger will harm you."
You and I, we've never meant to harm anyone.
But they want to take our lives.
I have to report this to His Majesty and the Empress.
There's no refuting the concrete evidence against Yu.
But I'm afraid His Majesty will still have feelings for her.
Her poison and curses didn't kill you, My Lady.
That might leave her with a reason to live.
But deceiving His Majesty is a capital offence.
My Lady, do you remember that I asked you
whether "fish eyes were passed off as pearls" on New Year's Eve?
Your Highness...
What is so urgent?
Xiao-Yinzi didn't return to Yu last night.
I was just informed that he entered
the Palace of Pearl Jade and never came out.
Useless eunuch!
Your Highness, that castrated pig must have
confessed everything under torture.
Escort Yu can't be saved.
What if she rats us out?
What do you suggest?
Finish one to end it all.
No!
It would only draw attention
if Your Highness made a move at this time.
She has to take this to her grave.
She wanted to kill Zhen Huan for her own revenge.
Given a chance to survive,
how could she not betray us?
She will choose her family's survival over her own.
Why did you take so long?
I had to try to make it clear.
I'm not an articulate maid.
You say, with your silver tongue.
Who here is cleverer than you?
You not only need to make it clear,
but also appeal to His Majesty emotionally, right?
Thank you for your advice, sir.
Ah, don't say that to an old friend!
What did His Majesty say?
You'll hear it yourself.
I'd be obliged for your help now.
Su Peisheng!
Who are you? How dare you break in like this?
By His Majesty's decree, Yu is banished to the Cold Palace.
I don't believe this! I don't believe this!
I need to see His Majesty! I need to see His Majesty!
His Majesty no longer cares to see you!
Go!
I don't believe this!
I need to see His Majesty!
I bow in respect before Your Majesty.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
- Rise.
- I thank Your Majesty.
Did you sleep well last night?
I thank Your Majesty.
I'm afraid it would be dangerous if I slept too well.
I understand.
Jinxi reported to me and the Empress this morning.
I will have your food and tonics
closely monitored from now on.
This won't be allowed to happen again.
It was also my fault to be so oblivious.
It wasn't your fault.
It was the rivalries in the harem,
more insidious than I could have imagined.
I had Spica and Xiao-Yinzi flogged to death.
And Yu will be confined in the Cold Palace
for the rest of her life.
Huan Huan, you are out of harm's way now.
I never meant to vie with anyone.
But so many people have died
because I offended Yu unintentionally.
I am a sinful concubine,
unworthy of Your Majesty's favor.
Don't overthink.
You've been the innocent victim of a series of appalling events.
Take it easy on yourself.
I made a wish on New Year's Eve,
hoping that the northern wind could spare the plum blossoms.
But my wish wasn't granted by Heaven.
Where did you make the wish?
And what did you say for your wish?
In the Garden of Leaning Plums on New Year's Eve.
I said, “If the northern wind can hear the plum flowers,
spare the blooming wishes for a peaceful spring."
It was difficult to walk in the snow.
I accidentally got my shoes wet.
Did you run into anyone?
Si Lang, how did you know?
That night, in the garden,
I came across a male stranger.
I was out without permission
and had to avoid contact with a male stranger,
I had to say that I was a maid working in the garden
to extricate myself.
Was the stranger that night...
I apologize for my ill manners.
I didn't know it was Your Majesty.
It was you?
So it was you!
I mistook you for someone else.
Su Peisheng!
Yes, Your Majesty.
Announce my decree:
Yu in the Cold Palace is granted suicide
for deceiving me and poisoning my concubine.
Yes, I'll do it immediately.
What was wrong, Your Majesty?
Why did you suddenly grant her suicide?
She lied to me, claiming that
she was the person who spoke to me that night.
She spread her climbing vines on imperial favors
and offended her superiors time and again.
Now her crimes are unpardonable.
Yu made mistakes because she admired Your Majesty.
An emperor cannot take back his words.
Yu is unpardonable.
But since you pleaded her case,
I will allow her corpse to be sent home.
I thank Your Majesty.
Did you bring a precious object with you
when you prayed in the garden that night?
A sachet, a fan pendant, or a flower hairpin?
Only the kind of trinket that girls like.
I can make another one for Si Lang if you like.
You've been unnerved lately.
Worry about that when you've restored your peace of mind.
I'm in no hurry. I have ample days ahead to spend with you.
There was one more thing I summoned you for.
The Ministry of Revenue proposed implementing
the Well-Field System.
The officials have varied opinions about the system.
I'd rather go investigate by myself
than listen to their endless debates.
I'll go to the suburbs.
The trip will only take a few days.
Farming is a matter of life and death for the people.
When will Your Majesty depart?
Everything's ready. I can leave right away.
Please take the best care of yourself during the trip.
I wanted to have Su Peisheng go with me,
but it's not so convenient for a eunuch to travel.
But don't worry, I traveled a lot for
the prior emperor when I was a State Prince.
Take care of yourself.
I'll be back in no time.
How is the task going with Lady Cao?
She's always quiet with her head down,
but she talks sense whenever she speaks.
She's been taking care of Yu's family.
She is thoughtful indeed.
What use will she be
if she can't even sort things out for Your Highness?
But you used to be a more favored concubine
when we were living in the estate.
Why's that different now?
Because Lady Cao... has a daughter.
So she can see His Majesty more often.
Yes, even having a daughter has its blessings.
Why is everyone so quiet today?
I feel suffocated.
What's wrong?
I hate being ambushed,
and I was resentful of Spica and Xiao-Yinzi.
But when His Majesty decreed their execution,
it didn't bring peace to my mind.
Me neither.
No one would take heart from the death of another.
We have just defeated one.
Who knows how many more we're yet to encounter?
Then we'll deal with them, one after another.
They won't be able to harm us as long as
we are of one heart and one mind.
But Sourire, why did you keep this from me?
I only heard about it from the Empress this morning
that Yu not only conspired against you
but also impersonated you, for favor.
I didn't mean to hide anything from you.
This was a frightful incident.
It's better to know as little as possible.
But I see you as my own sister.
If my sister gets into trouble,
how can I not know about it?
Fortunately, this is over.
I'm grateful that you are fine.
His Majesty has granted suicide to Yu.
That is the fate of anyone who intends us harm.
Soft-spoken as she is,
Lingrong has a strong mind.
My Lady!
Yu refuses to commit suicide.
She's kicking up a row in the Cold Palace,
yelling that she must see His Majesty one last time.
How?
His Majesty must be outside the palace gates by now.
Then she'll be kept alive until His Majesty returns?
Has this been reported to the Empress?
Her Majesty has been bed-ridden due to severe migraine attacks.
She won't take care of this.
In that case, only Consort Fleur is in charge...
Consort Fleur's palace said nothing other than that
she's been indisposed.
She was close to Yu.
Now she wants to flee from any connection
with her whatsoever.
Yu insists that she's been slandered.
She smashed the poison and acted insane.
She curses My Lady viciously in the Cold Palace,
using words unbearable to hear.
Let her be. She's flailing before the gallows.
Sourire, I think it's time that I should return.
- Take care.
- Goodbye, Lingrong.
Coua, what is the Cold Palace?
It is the palace for the banished concubines.
Many of them ended up dead or deranged
in their confinement there.
It is considered a haunted place with excessive yin.
Hence the name Cold Palace.
So no one visits the Cold Palace?
What kind of hell is that place?
Servants who lived near the Cold Palace repeatedly saw
ghosts that kept crying night after night.
It's horrifying.
I will go for a visit.
My Lady, let's not go inside. It's frightening.
(Let me go! Let go!)
Let me go! Let go of me!
Yu, accept your fate.
Let go!
Let me go!
What brought you here, Companion An?
Sourire heard that Yu has been cursing her.
She sent me here to see what's going on.
Let me go! Let go!
It seems that you haven't finished the job, sir?
She's making a scene.
Why are you here?
Why are you here!
Where is His Majesty?
Let me go!
Pull her away!
Why would His Majesty
set his noble foot into the Cold Palace?
It was Zhen Huan!
It was all because of that bitch!
She lured His Majesty into killing me!
I suppose you are refusing suicide
because you want to know why.
I'll do the favor of telling you.
It was you who tampered with Sourire's tonics, wasn't it?
Yes, I arranged that.
But it was her who made me fall from grace
to this pitiful existence!
I wish I could drink her blood and chew her bones.
So that bitch will live in hell, life after life!
You wish?
“The winner becomes king, the defeated an outlaw."
No, I must not die.
I met His Majesty on New Year's Eve.
His Majesty likes to hear me sing Kunqu Opera.
He doesn't have the heart to kill me.
“If the northern wind can hear the plum flowers,
spare the blooming wishes for a peaceful spring."
You stole Sourire's favor. How do you have
the shamelessness to keep on living?
It was her... It was her!
No, I must not die.
I must not die!
Your Majesty... Your Majesty...
You like my Kunqu Opera.
Sir, may I have a word with you?
I will sing Kunqu for Your Majesty!
My Lady.
His Majesty is away and the Empress is having a migraine attack.
This madness must be stopped.
Your Majesty...
My Lady, Yu was granted suicide.
But this madwoman smashed
the poison and tore up the white silk.
There's nothing we can do about her.
Sir, you have served His Majesty for a long time, haven't you?
Yes, for over thirty years.
Sir, you are the most knowledgeable person in the palace
and much appreciated for your hard work.
You understand His Majesty the best.
Now that His Majesty has left the palace,
are you keeping her alive until he returns?
My Lady, you're suggesting...
Sir, your work is done when she is dead.
No one would investigate how she died.
For instance, what would happen if a concubine refused
the decree to be buried alive with a deceased emperor?
My Lady, I understand.
Sir, I'm sure you understand
"one has more dreams the longer he sleeps".
If her life comes to end,
it'll put an end to His Majesty's concern.
Yes. I bid you goodbye, My Lady.
Your Majesty... Help me, Your Majesty!
Your Majesty...
Zhen Huan, you didn't die in my hands
but someone else will finish you!
You will die in hell!
Still impenitent when death befalls her!
Yu will certainly die, but why would you
make a trip to this blood-curdling place, My Lady?
I want Sourire to know
that I did this all for her.
You never treated eunuchs as humans.
But look who you ended up with.
- Xiao-Xiazi.
- Yes.
I told you to be tolerant of her before.
But now, no more.
No! No!
I am His Majesty's concubine.
You cannot kill me!
Peace to Lady Sourire.
Peace to Lady Shen.
I came to report to you that Yu committed suicide.
It's good that it's over.
Just a twang on the bowstring - quick and clean.
Nothing to worry about, My Lady.
Bowstring?
My Lady, you sent Companion An over, didn't you?
Yu made a huge row.
Companion An said Yu had to die anyway
and suggested we strangle her.
You strangled her?
Yes.
It was Companion An's idea?
Otherwise, shifu wouldn't have thought of that.
But no one likes Yu. Nobody will say anything.
- Good. You can go now.
- I bid you goodbye.
- My Lady.
- Are you all right?
Are you all right, My Lady?
She's already dead.
Why did he say such disgusting words?
My Lady, the smell of the incense will make you feel better.
Peace to Companion An.
Where's Sourire?
My Lady is having tea with Lady Shen.
I will report that you are here.
No need. It's just as well,
because I want some tea.
I'll see myself in.
Meizhuang, did I go too far in this?
"I don't offend those who don't offend me."
But I couldn't imagine that
Lingrong would be so hard-hearted about it.
Lingrong did it for us.
Killing is all too common in the palace.
If one's heart is not hard enough,
others will only be tougher.
This all started with you.
Lingrong wasn't involved at all.
But now, she has gone to the Cold Palace
and had Yu strangled.
That's not the girl I know.
I thought she was more delicate.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Phoenix Taking Flight
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
The dreams I dimly recall;
The past I hardly remember,
amidst the autumn moons and the spring flowers.
Like the moon's reflection on water
or flowers seen through mist - floating and drifting.
The joyous sounds you brought;
The silence you left;
Changing faster than clouds can turn to rain.
Our minds resonated;
Our hearts beat in unison;
But we lost what we once possessed.
A poem to converse;
A melody to accompany;
A heart to bind to mine.
I hoped for endless longing and eternal promise,
but I’m left with only the flute and the zither.
With affection, I pleased;
With my heart, I committed;
With my arms, I embraced.
I desired to be remembered;
Desired to be cherished;
Why am I only hated and deceived?
My wish ran against my will.
Behold the mockery of destiny and the game of fate.
My unwavering love is gone
like flowers swept away in the wind.
Praying for a bright moon;
Praying for a rising sun;
Dreaming to bask in the spring breezes.
But the unsparing northern winds carry snow and rain
to destroy the aspirations of the plum tree.
A phoenix about to take flight rustles its wings
but the arc of its flight is unseen.
The phoenix tree sways in the wind,
shedding memories in the whispers of the falling leaves.